Max Meyer Papers 5221
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Max Meyer Papers
1925-1979
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Meyer, Max
5221
4.5 cubic feet
4.5 linear ft.
Papers (documents).
Papers documenting Meyer's work as Chairman of the NRA, Millinery Code Authority and later Chairman of the Millinery Stabilization Commission, as well as other aspects of his career (as banker, arbitrator, and community leader).
3338497
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
CB, April 29, 1999
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, February 21, 2017
Biographical / Historical
1876 Born March 29.
1910 Member, employees group which negotiated "Protocol of Peace".
1918 Founded, Urban League of White Plains, New York.
1920's Secretary, Industrial Council of the Cloak, Suit and Skirt Manufacturers Protective Association.
1929 Retired as partner of A. Beller and Co.
1931 Gov. Franklin D. Roosevelt named Meyer to Commission to study medical treatment for workers under workers' compensation.
1931 Member, State Industrial Council.
1933 Member, Labor Board of NRA.
1934 Chairman, Millinery Code Authority, NRA.
1934 Head, Hotel and Restaurant Minimum Wage Board, NYSDOL.
1937 Chairman, Millinery Stabilization Commission.
1937 Member, NYS Board of Mediation.
1940 Chairman, Needlecraft Educational Commission (Advisory Board for Central High School Needle Trades).
1945 Chairman, Educational Foundation, Apparel Industry.
1951 Chairman, Board of Trustees, Fashion Institute of Technology.
1952 President, Fashion Institute of Technology.
1953 Died January 31.
Scope and Contents
The major portion of this collection covers the period 1934-1938 at which time Meyer was Chairman of the NRA, Millinery Code Authority and later Chairman of the Millinery Stabilization Commission. However, items covering other aspects of his career (as banker, arbitrator, and community leader) can be found throughout the collection.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5192: Paul Abelson Papers 5437 OH: Paul Abelson Interview Conducted by Jesse Carpenter 5807: Paul Abelson Additional Records 6165 mf: Paul Abelson Files on Microfilm
Meyer, Max, 1876-1953
3338497
- A - General, 1934-1953 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Re: appointment on National Panel of Arbitrators of American Arbitrators Association, with Paul Abelson; with Dean Acheson, (Secretary of State), and routine.
- Administrative and Executive Orders, Washington, D.C., 1934-1935 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Includes copies of Orders of Code of Fair Competition for the Millinery Industry; letters from National Recovery Administration, H. Rose, Chief, Code Record Section, re appointment of Meyer as Director and Chairman of the Code Authority of the Millinery Industry, 1/8/35 and routine.
- Amendments, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Routine.
- Annual Report - Letters of Commendation, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Includes letters from various individuals thanking Meyer for sending copies of the 1st Annual Report of the Code Authority of the Millinery Industry.
- Apparel Codes Label Council, 1934-1935 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Correspondence with Bessie Beatty, Secretary of the Council regarding garment labels, meetings; by-laws and reports.
- Apparel Industries Committee for the renewal of N.R.A., 1935 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Correspondence re lobbying for extension of N.R.A. by Code members.
- Applicants (Part 1 of 2), 1937-1941 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Many letters of recommendation for employment of immigrants and others from Meyer; correspondence from Frances Perkins (10/3/38) in the form of a recommendation for employment of an acquaintence.
- Applicants (Part 2 of 2), 1937-1942 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Applications, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  re applications from individuals for employment with Code Authority.
- Apprentices, 1934-1935 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Information re apprentice training from Federal Committee on Apprentice Training.
- Arbitrations, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Correspondence re dates for hearings and miscellaneous.
- Artificial Flower and Feather Industries of America (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Associated Merchandising Group (P.J. Reilly), 1934 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  re N.R.A. labels.
- B - General, 1934-1951 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  re Henri Bendel, Inc. case before NLRB; with Paul F. Brissenden re dedication of Fashion Institute of Technology (1951) and others.
- Barenboim, A.H., 1935 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Bergdorf Goodman and Co., 1934-1935 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Birthday Ball - Replies, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  Meyer, Chairman, Industry Committee for Birthday Ball for the President (Roosevelt) to raise funds for research to combat infantile paralysis.
- Brandeis, Louis D. (Supreme Court Justice), 1934-1937 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  Personal Correspondence.
- Budget, 1934-1935 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  Printed budget of the "Code Authority of the Millinery Industry" January-June 1935 and other financial information.
- Butwig, Sam, 1934-1936 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Bulletins and Letters for Industry, 1934-1935 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  Code of Authority form letter sent out by Meyer; two issues of "Code Authority News" (1934) and publications.
- By-Laws, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Includes certificate of Incorporation and By-laws of the National Millinery Code Authority.
- C - General, 1934-1935 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Carr, Harry C., 1934-1935 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  (Deputy Administrator, N.R.A.) re routine.
- Chicago Injunction Suit, 1934-1935 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  Rre suit filed by Chicago Millinery Manufacturers against the Code Authority.
- Coat and Suit Code Authority, 1934-1935 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  re regulations covering use of labels and routine.
- Confidential, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  re Chicago Injunction Suit and expenditures by Code Authority staff.
- Constangy, Frank A., 1935 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Contractors, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Coonley, Prentiss L., 1934-1935 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  Routine. (Code Administration Director, N.R.A.)
- Cotton Garment Industry, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- D - General, 1933-1937 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  Includes correspondence with Mary Drier and David Dubinsky, routine.
- Daily Reports, 1934-1935 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  Completed report forms.
- Dallas Injunction, 1934-1935 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  re violations of wage and hour provisions of the Code.
- Davis, James P., 1934-1935 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  (Chairman, Special Millinery Board) routine.
- Definitions, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  re definition of a "cutter" and routine.
- Dreschler, David, 1934-1935 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  (Counsel, Millinery Code Authority) routine.
- E - General 1934-35, 1934-1935 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  Includes correspondence re extension of N.R.A. and routine.
- F- General, 1934-1935 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  Includes correspondence and radio addresses, Edward L. Fries, Label Review Officer, Compliance Director, N.R.A. and routine.
- Falk, Emile S., 1934-1935 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  Correspondence with Falk, (Catalina Hats, Ltd.) member, Code Authority for the Pacific Coast re market conditions and code enforcements and routine.
- Fashion Institute of Technology, 1945-1979 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  Correspondence, newsletter, clippings, release, history.
- Fashion Show, 1934 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Finkenberg and Sons (Edward), 1937 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  Re labor problems and subsequent strike.
- G - General, 1935 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  re code violations and routine.
- General - Correspondence (Box 3, Folder 8)
  Letters sent to Code Authority members.
- H - General, 1925-1947 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  Report on Hudson River State Hospital (NYS Commission on Mental Hygiene); Letter from Morris Hillquit (1925).
- Hat Corporation of America, 1934-1935 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  Correspondence re granting exemption of the Code of Fair Competition.
- Hats and Caps, 1934-1935 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  Includes 18 page report - "Special Commission Studying Labor Conditions in the Cap and Cloth Hat Industry"; Correspondence with Paul F. Brissenden, (Chairman of Special Commission for Cap and Cloth Hat Industry), re Commission findings; and routine.
- Herstein, Dave, 1934-1935 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  Chairman, Millinery Quality Guild re routine.
- High School of Fashion Industries, 1936-1978 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  Correspondence, clippings, newsletters, programs, letter from Eleanor Roosevelt re murals by Ernest Fience in Auditorium of High School.
- Hillman, Sidney, 1940-1944 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  Letter from Meyer to Reporter Dispatch criticizing an editorial about Hillman and routine.
- I - General, 1934-1935 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  Correspondence, meeting announcements and minutes of New York State Industrial Council and routine.
- Industrial Bulletin, 1949-1952 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  Re achievements in the garment industry including Meyer's contribution.
- Industrial Council (NYS) (Part 1 of 2), 1937-1952 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  Correspondence re minimum wage law, longshoreman strike and routine business. With Edward Corsi, Industrial Commissioner. With Frieda S. Miller, Industrial Commissioner; Rose Schneiderman, Secretary. Also: Includes minutes.
- Industrial Council (NYS) (Part 2 of 2), 1937-1953 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Infant's and Children's Wear Code Authority (Part 1 of 2), 1933-1935 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  re jurisdiction controversy between Infants Code and Millinery Code; Includes Conference minutes and related documents; also correspondence with Maxwell Copelof, Director of Code Authority, Infants and Children's Wear, and others.
- Infant's and Children's Wear Code Authority (Part 2 of 2), 1933-1935 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Inter-Industry Board - Retail Custom Millinery Trade, 1935 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  Correspondence with Paul F. Brissenden, Chairman of the Board, and others.
- Inter-Office Correspondence - Miscellaneous, 1935 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Investigation Committee, 1934 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  re the operation of the Code Authority - includes reports and minutes.
- J - General, 1935 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Jacob, Andrew A., 1934-1935 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  Divisional Supervisor of Code, San Francisco re Continuance of N.R.A., Firms on strike in Los Angeles; Reports and routine.
- K - General, 1934-1935 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Knitted Outerwear, 1934-1935 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  re Homework regulations; Code overlapping controversy between Knitted Industry and Millinery Industry.
- Knitted Outerwear, 1934-1935 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Kraftsow, George (Box 4, Folder 11)
- L - General, 1934-1935 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Label Sales Report (Box 4, Folder 13)
  Includes statistical information.
- LaGuardia, Fiorelli H., 1945 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  Personal letter from Meyer.
- Laundry Board, 1949-1950 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  Correspondence re arbitration matters.
- Lehman, Herbert H. (Governor of NY), 1934-1965 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  Includes letters to Meyer's daughter as well as Mr. Meyer re personal.
- Leslie, Harold (Legal Division, Millinery Code), 1934-1935 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  Inter-office correspondence re violations.
- Lewis, Jasper R.(Executive Secretary, Millinery Code Authority), 1934-1935 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  Inter-office correspondence.
- Lindau, Constance, 1937-1952 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  personal re arbitration and miscellaneous.
- Lipshie, Joseph, 1934-1935 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  Includes reports and inter-office correspondence.
- Lists (Box 5, Folder 1)
  Lists of committees and members; miscellaneous.
- Lowenstein, Sidney (Deputy Code Director, Millinery Industry), 1934-1935 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  Routine business correspondence.
- Lopin, Maxwell E. (Attorney), 1934-1935 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  re routine legal matters.
- Mc (Box 5, Folder 4)
  routine.
- M - General, 1934-1948 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  with George Meany, President, New York State Federation of Labor and routine business correspondence.
- Miller, Frieda S., 1936-1952 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  (Director, Division of Women in Industry, New York State Department of Labor) and later Industry Commissioner. Re personal and business correspondence.
- Millinery Institute, 1934 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  re demand for a stay on the Labor provisions of the Code.
- Millinery Manufacturers of New Jersey (Part 1 of 2), 1934-1935 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  Correspondence re proposed National Millinery
- Millinery Manufacturers of New Jersey (Part 2 of 2), 1934-1935 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  Association and routine.
- Millinery Stabilization Committee (Part 1 of 2), 1937-1952 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  Includes reports, correspondence concerning the difficulties in the industry; ten page speech by Meyer; resolutions and miscellaneous.
- Millinery Stabilization Committee (Part 2 of 2), 1937-1952 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Minimum Wage Boards - Hotel and Restaurant, 1935-1940 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  (Meyer, Member) Correspondence with Frieda Miller, Director of Division of Women in Industry, re wages and hours in hotels and restaurants and other related correspondence.
- Montgomery, F.H. (President, Hat Corporation of America), 1935 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- N - General, 1935 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  Correspondence with Julius Frank, President, National Straw Works (Wisconsin) re problems with business; New York City Board of Education and routine.
- National Conference for Clarifying the Constitution By Amendment, 1937 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  Includes minutes of Planning Committee; and correspondence.
- National Industrial Recovery Act, 1933-1934 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- National Millinery Association, 1935 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  Includes Agreement, By-laws, correspondence and routine.
- National Recovery Administration - Millinery Code (Part 1 of 5), 1937 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  Meyer, Impartial Chairman, re case between Nedick's and the union. Includes correspondence, decision, agreement.
- National Recovery Administration - Millinery Code (Part 2 of 5), 1937 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- National Recovery Administration - Millinery Code (Part 3 of 5), 1937 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- National Recovery Administration - Millinery Code (Part 4 of 5), 1937 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- National Recovery Administration - Millinery Code (Part 5 of 5), 1937 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Nedick's Stores, Inc. (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Nelson, D.M. (Director, Code Administration, N.R.A.), 1934-1935 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  Routine correspondence.
- Neustadt, Richard M., 1934-1935 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  Routine personal and business.
- New York Child Labor Committee, 1938-1941 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  Correspondence re vocational education; creation of a State Youth Service Commission, possible merger with National Child Labor Committee; dissolution of the committee; and other related matters.
- New York State Board of Mediation (Part 1 of 3), 1937-1948 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  Correspondence re various cases with Specialty Bakery Owners of America, Bloomingdale's, D.A. Schultze, Inc., Stern Brothers, United Cigar-Whelan Stores Corp., Greenwood Cemetary and others. Correspondence re Ives Joint Legislative Committee; other related correspondence.
- New York State Board of Mediation (Part 2 of 3), 1937-1948 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- New York State Board of Mediation (Part 3 of 3), 1937-1948 (Box 7, Folder 7)
- New York State Commission Against Discrimination, 1938-1953 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  Alleged discrimination in American Legion membership, hospitals, building trade unions in Westchester County; and routine.
- New York State Labor Department, 1935-1938 (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Newman, Pauline (Educational Director, Union Health Center), 1948-1952 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  re Joint Board of Sanitary Control and other personal and related correspondence.
- Notices of meetings, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Oppenheim, Burton E. (Deputy Administrator, Textile Division, N.R.A.), 1934-1940 (Box 7, Folder 12)
- Oriole Hat Company, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 13)
- P - General, 1934-1935 (Box 7, Folder 14)
- Perkins, Frances (New York State Industrial Commissioner; Secretary of Labor), 1930-1953 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  Personal and routine.
- R - General, 1925-1935 (Box 7, Folder 16)
- Retail Milliners, 1934-1935 (Box 7, Folder 17)
- Roosevelt, Franklin D., 1928-1948 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  Correspondence re problems in the Millinery Industry. Also letter from Eleanor Roosevelt thanking Meyer for sending her his speech; includes a group photograph (unidentified) except for Roosevelt.
- Rosenberg, Anna M. (State N.R.A. Compliance Director), 1934-1952 (Box 7, Folder 19)
- Rosenfeld, William H. (Deputy Code Director, Millinery Industry), 1934-1935 (Box 7, Folder 20)
- S - General, 1934-1935 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Schachter, H.C., 1934-1935 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Schwartz, Nicholas, 1934-1935 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Social Security Act, 1937 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  Correspondence with Edward Keating, Editor, Labor re insurance and exemption of bank employees from Social Security Law and other related matters.
- Schwellenbach, Louis B. (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Sherman, George A. (Sherman Hat Co.), 1935 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  Discussion of a National Millinery Association.
- Stabilization Program - Votes, 1935 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  Includes 18 page report, "Planning and Education Program for the Millinery Industry", 1934 and routine.
- Sternberg, Jerome A. (President, Associated Millinery Industries, St. Louis), 1935 (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Strauss, Percy S. (President, R.H. Macy and Company), 1935 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  re refusal to pay for trade name labels and routine.
- T - General, 1934-1935 (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Tark, L. Shirley (Deputy Code Director, Millinery Industry), 1934-1935 (Box 8, Folder 11)
- Taylor, Thomas R. (Industrial Advisory Board, N.R.A.), 1934-1935 (Box 8, Folder 12)
- Thomas, Norman, 1948 (Box 8, Folder 13)
- Thompson, L.D. (President, Southern Millinery Manufacturers Association), 1934-1935 (Box 8, Folder 14)
- Tofias, George I. (Code Authority for New England, 1934-1935 (Box 8, Folder 15)
- Trade Name Label - Replies to Letter Sent to Retailers, 1934 (Box 8, Folder 16)
- Truman, Harry S., 1953 (Box 8, Folder 17)
- U-V - General, 1934-1935 (Box 8, Folder 18)
- Vincent, M.D. (Deputy Administrator, N.R.A.), 1934-1935 (Box 8, Folder 19)
- Vocational Education, 1931-1952 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  Includes Correspondence, programs, clippings, addresses by Meyer - (Meyer received award (1939) for his contribution to vocational education in New York State).
- Vocational Education, 1931-1952 (Box 8, Folder 21)
- W- General, 1926-1935 (Box 8, Folder 22)
- Walther - Reports, 1934 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  Includes Compliance Division Report.
- War Labor Board, 1943-1944 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  Includes case - Meyer, Referee, before WLB and routine.
- Washington - Miscellaneous, 1937-1944 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  Includes correspondence arranging appointments with Frances Perkins, Eleanor Roosevelt and others; and routine.
- Weinzweig, I. - Inter-Office Correspondence, 1934-1935 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  (Supervisor of Inspection Division, Code Millinery). Re problems of inspection division; violations of the Code and routine.
- Westchester (Co.) Medical Society, 1948 (Box 8, Folder 27)
- Wholesale Millinery Trade Code Authority, 1934-1935 (Box 8, Folder 28)
- Women's Headwear Group, Inc. (Eastern Women's Headwear Association), 1934-1935 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  Correspondence in opposition to renewal of Code Authority for Millinery Industry from J.E. Helper, Secretary, Women's Headwear Group.
- Workmen's Compensation, 1932-1947 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  Includes letter from Franklin D. Roosevelt, Governor of New York State, asking Meyer to serve another year on the Committee to Review Medical and Hospital Problems in connection with Workmen's Compensation; Correspondence with Mary Donlon, Chairman, Worker's Compensation Board, New York State re medical education; and routine.
- Worthy, James C. (Assistant Deputy Administrator, Textile Division, N.R.A.), 1934-1935 (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Y-Z, 1934-1935 (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Zaritsky, Max (President, United Hatters, Cap and Millinery Workers International Union), 1934-1951 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  Includes personal and business correspondence.
- Meyer - Personal, 1934-1952 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  Includes 4 page "Recollections of Max Meyer" by Ben Aaron(?); personal correspondence with Julius H. Cohen, Paul Herzog, Marian Harron, Mabel Leslie; and other family members.
- Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1927-1939 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  Includes confidential correspondence (1930) from J.W. Johnston, Rochester, New York offering assistance to Meyer and Governor Roosevelt's administration and routine and personal.
- Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1940-1941 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  Letter from Louis Brandeis (1940); personal correspondence with Morris Crawford, editor, Women's Wear Daily; substantial correspondence with Alpheus Mason, Princeton University, and others concerning information on the life of Justice Louis Brandeis for Mason's book; Mason particularly requests recollections from Meyer regarding 1910 Protocol Agreement and other miscellaneous.
- Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1942-1947 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  Includes additional correspondence re search for information on Brandeis for Alpheus Mason; with Louis Stark (New York Times) suggesting a national labor commission to handle complaints of union members (1945); medical care; re denunciation of editorial on Franklin D. Roosevelt; and other miscellaneous.
- Miscellaneous Correspondence (Box 9, Folder 9)
  Correspondence with George V. Taylor and miscellaneous.
- Miscellaneous Correspondence (Box 9, Folder 10)
- Miscellaneous Correspondence (Box 9, Folder 11)
- Miscellaneous Correspondence (Box 9, Folder 12)
- Speeches, 1935-1952 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  Includes addresses before conventions, meetings, graduation exercises; and other events.
- Miscellaneous, 1935 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  Contains schedules, drafts, handwritten notes.
- Cases, 1934-1942 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  William F. Chinquy Co.; Bloomingdale Bros.; and M. Walker
- Publications (Box 9, Folder 16)
  "History In The Making" by Max Meyer (1948); Typewritten messages (1940's); Articles and clippings re Meyer.
- Biography of Meyer, 1947 (Box 9, Folder 17)
- Condolence Letters, Memorial Services, Obituaries, 1953-1979 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  Includes letters from Frances Perkins, Eleanor Roosevelt, Herbert Lehman and many other notable individuals.
- Condolence Letters, Memorial Services, Obituaries, 1953-1979 (Box 9, Folder 19)
- Text digitized from the collection. (Box 10)